Catherine Viviano Gallery Records
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Catherine Viviano Gallery records
1930-1990, bulk 1949-1978.
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Catherine Viviano
11.6 linear feet
The records of the Catherine Viviano Gallery measure 11.6 linear feet and date from 1930-1990, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1949-1978. Established in New York City in 1949, the gallery specialized in contemporary painting and sculpture primarily by American and European artists. The collection consists of artists' files; correspondence with artists, collectors, dealers, museum directors, curators, and publishers; business records; printed material; and photographs of artwork and artists. Also included are records relating to Catherine Viviano's activities as a private dealer and consultant after she closed the gallery in 1970.
Provenance
The Catherine Viviano Gallery records were donated in 2003 on behalf of Margaret Viviano, Catherine Viviano's sister, by her grandnephew, Peter C. Salerno, who had Power of Attorney for Margaret Viviano.
Related Material
Among the other resources relating to Catherine Viviano Gallery in the Archives of American Art are the Kay Sage papers, 1925-circa 1985, bulk 1950-1965.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
Catherine Viviano (1889-1992) opened her gallery in 1949 on 42 East 57th Street in New York City. Specializing in contemporary American paintings and sculpture, the gallery featured younger American and European artists, e.g., Robert Broderson, Carlyle Brown, Jan Cox, Joseph Glasco, Peter Lanyon, Manabu Mabe, César Manrique, Bernard Perlin, Joseph Rollo, Bernard Rosenthal, and Kay Sage, among others. The gallery was also notable for introducing the work of Italian artists, who had been cut off from the American art scene during World War II, including Afro Basaldella and his brother Mirko Basaldella, Renato Birolli, Leonardo Cremonini, and Luciano Minguzzi.
Born in Italy in 1899 and raised in Chicago, Catherine Viviano came to New York in the early 1930's to work at the Pierre Matisse Gallery, where she remained for sixteen years before founding the Catherine Viviano Gallery.
In 1970, Catherine Viviano closed the gallery, though she continued to work from her home as an art dealer and consultant. She died of a stroke at the age of ninety-two in 1992.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Catherine Viviano Gallery measure 11.6 linear feet and date from 1930-1990, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1949-1978. Established in New York City in 1949, the gallery specialized in contemporary painting and sculpture primarily by American and European artists. The collection consists of artists' files; correspondence with artists, collectors, dealers, museum directors, curators, and publishers; business records; printed material; and photographs of artwork and artists. Also included are records relating to Catherine Viviano's activities as a private dealer and consultant after she closed the gallery in 1970.
Artists' files include biographical material; artists' statements; correspondence; sales and expense reports; lists and notes; guest lists; writings by others; receipts, invoices, and statements; printed material, including press releases, exhibition announcements, brochures, catalogues, clippings; and photographs of artwork and artists. Included are extensive files on Afro Basaldella, Renato Birolli, Robert Broderson, Anselmo Franesconi, Joseph Glasco, Manabu Mabe, César Manrique, Luciano Minguzzi, Ennio Morlotti, Bernard Perlin, Daniel Rice, and Bernard Rosenthal. There are also files on Jan Cox, Kay Sage, and Kazuo Wakabayashi.
Correspondence comprises the largest series in the collection and consists of general correspondence; correspondence with museums, galleries, and art-related institutions in the United States; and correspondence with museums, galleries, and art-related institutions abroad. Letters focus on routine business matters, e.g., appraisals and sales, acquisitions, and organizing exhibitions at the Catherine Viviano Gallery and other venues.
General correspondence includes letters between Catherine Viviano and artists and their family members. Among the correspondents are: Mary Callery, Bernard Chaet, Piero and Virginia Dorazio, Jean Dubuffet, Dallas Ernst, Karl Fortress, Alberto Giacometti, Henry Sage Goodwin, Morris Graves, José Guerrero, Earle Ludgin, Joan Miro, Alfonso Ossorio, Dorothea Tanning, Stuyvesant Van Veen, Adja Yunkers and his wife, Dore Ashton, among others. Also found is Viviano's correspondence with clients, many of whom were prominent collectors, e.g., Richard Brown Baker, Carl and Joan Fisher, Lawrence and Barbara Fleischman, Joseph Hirschhorn, Marc Moyens, Vincent Price, Joseph Pulitzer, Jr., Nelson Rockefeller, Stanley Seeger, and Frederick and Dorothy Zimmerman. Of interest, are letters from Elizabeth Bishop inquiring about the purchase of a work of art from the gallery. Included are letters from art historians, museum directors, curators, representatives at other art-related institutions, and publishers including Walter Bareiss, Walter Barker, Dominque De Menil, Valentine Dudensing, William Eisendrath, S. Lane Faison, Emily Genauer, Bertram Goodhue, Erhard and Barbara Göpel, James Laughlin, Porter McCray, Abram Lerner, Doris Meltzer, Stephen Robson Miller, John Bernard Myers, Perry Rathbone, Belle Krasne Ribicoff, Meyer Shapiro, George Stout, and Curt Valentin.
Correspondence with museums, galleries, and art-related institutions in the United States contains letters between Viviano and museum directors, curators, dealers, artists, and collectors pertaining to loans, shipping and delivery of artwork, appraisals and sales, and acquisitions. Files include substantive correspondence with the American Academy of Arts and Letters, American Federation of the Arts, Art Institute of Chicago, Arts Club of Chicago, the Barnes Foundation, Bristol Art Museum, Brooklyn Museum, Bundy Art Gallery, Carnegie Institute, City Art Museum of St. Louis, Cleveland Museum of Art, Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, Denver Art Museum, Des Moines Art Center, Detroit Institute of Arts, Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University, Hirschhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, Institute of Contemporary Art, Los Angeles County Art Museum, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Metropolitan Museum of Art, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, Museum of Modern Art, Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Philadelphia Art Alliance, Santa Barbara Museum of Art, University of Nebraska Art Galleries, University of Virginia, Mary Washington College, Wadsworth Atheneum, Walker Art Center, William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, Atkins Museum of the Fine Arts, World House Gallery, and Yale University Art Library.
Correspondence with museums, galleries, and art-related institutions abroad primarily concerns the lending of artwork for exhibitions, acquisition and sales; also included are letters requesting biographical information on artists. Letters between Catherine Viviano and representatives of Max Beckmann Gesellschaft Archiv and Galerie Gunther Franke contain provenance-related information on Beckmann's work.
Business records document the routine business operations of the gallery. Printed material includes an incomplete run of Catherine Viviano Gallery exhibition catalogues; invitations and announcements from other galleries and institutions; and miscellaneous printed material.
Photographs include three images of miscellaneous artwork used for art reference.
Arrangement
Records are generally arranged by material type and in chronological order thereafter. Artists' files and correspondence files are arranged in alphabetical order and materials within the folders are arranged chronologically
The collection is arranged as 5 series:
Series 1: Artists' Files, 1945-1986 (Boxes 1-3; 3.5 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1939-1985 (Boxes 3-6; 5.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Business Records, 1949-1972 (Boxes 10-11; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 4: Printed Material, 1930-1990 (Boxes 11-13; 1.6 linear feet)
Series 5: Photographs (1948-1954), undated (Box 14; 1 folder)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Afro, 1912-1976; Birolli, Renato, 1905?-1959; Broderson, Robert M, 1920-; Cox, Jan, 1919-1980; Glasco, Joseph, 1925-; Mabe, Manabu; Manrique, César, 1920-; Minguzzi, Luciano, 1911-; Morlotti, Ennio, 1910-1992; Perlin, Bernard, 1918-; Rosenthal, Bernard M.; Sage, Kay; Wakabayashi, Kazuo
Subjects-Topical:
Art--Collectors and collecting; Art dealers; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Painting; Sculpture
Types of Materials:
Notes; Photographs
Names:
Ashton, Dore; Baker, Richard Brown; Bareiss, Walter; Barker, Walter; Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979; Callery, Mary, 1903-1977; Chaet, Bernard; Dorazio, Piero, 1927-; Dorazio, Virginia Dortch; Dubuffet, Jean, 1901-; Dudensing, F. Valentine, 1901-ca. 1960; Eisendrath, William N., 1903-; Ernst, Dallas; Faison, S. Lane (Samson Lane), 1907-2006; Fleischman, Barbara; Fleischman, Lawrence A. (Lawrence Arthur), 1925-1997; Genauer, Emily, 1910-; Giacometti, Alberto, 1901-1966; Goodhue, Bertram Grosvenor, 1869-1924; Göpel, Barbara; Göpel, Erhard; Graves, Morris, 1910-; Guerrero, José, 1914-; Hirschhorn, Joseph; Lerner, Abe, 1908-; Ludgin, Earle, 1898-1981; McCray, Porter A., 1908-2000; Meltzer, Doris, 1908-1977; Menil, Dominique de; Miller, Stephen Robeson; Miró, Joan, 1893-; Moyens, H. Marc; Myers, John Bernard; Ossorio, Alfonso, 1916-; Price, Vincent, 1911-; Pulitzer, Joseph, 1913-; Rathbone, Perry Townsend, 1911-2000; Ribicoff, Belle Krasne, 1924-; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979; Seeger, Stanley J.; Shapiro, Meyer; Stout, George L. (George Leslie); Tanning, Dorothea, 1910-; Van Veen, Stuyvesant; Valentin, Curt, 1902-1954; Viviano, Catherine.; Yunkers, Adja, 1900-1983
American Academy of Arts and Letters; American Federation of Arts; Art Club of Chicago; Art Institute of Chicago; Barnes Foundation; Brooklyn Museum; Carnegie Institute; City Art Museum of St. Louis; Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center; Dallas Museum of Fine Arts; Des Moines Art Center; Detroit Institute of Arts; Fogg Art Museum; Harvard University; Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden; Los Angeles County Museum; Mary Washington College; Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); Museum of Fine Arts, Boston; Museum of Fine Arts, Houston; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts; Philadelphia Art Alliance; Santa Barbara Museum of Art; University of Virginia; Wadsworth Atheneum; Walker Art Center; William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art and Mary Atkins Museum of Fine Arts; World House Galleries; Yale University. Art and Architecture Library
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Artists' Files, 1945-1986, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-3; 3.5 linear feet)
  Artists' files include: biographical material; correspondence; sales of artwork; guest lists; notes and writings; business-related material; printed matter, e.g., exhibition catalogues, brochures, clippings, press releases, reproductions; and photographs of artwork and artists.
  Biographical material contains curriculum vitae and artists' statements. Correspondence consists of letters, postcards, greeting cards, and telegrams between Viviano and artists, their family members, collectors, dealers, museum representatives, art historians, and others. Correspondence, for the most part, concerns sales, market valuations, and scheduling of exhibitions. Letters reflect the personal relationships that Viviano developed with many of the gallery's artists and collectors. Correspondence also includes business-related materials such as invoices, shipping receipts and statements, invoices, sales and expense reports, and miscellaneous legal claims.
  There are substantive files on Renato Birolli, Robert Broderson, Joseph Glasco, Manabu Mabe, César Manrique, Luciano Minguzzi, Ennio Morlotti, Bernard Perlin, Daniel Rice, and Bernard Rosenthal. Miscellaneous artists' files include biographical materials, checklists, consignment sale slips from the Grand Street Settlement, a typescript on Max Beckmann, notes, lists, and exhibition catalogues.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by artist and materials within the folders are in chronological order. Artists' files for which numerous documents are found are further divided by type of material.
  - Basaldella, Afro (Box 1)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1950-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lists of Artwork in Museums, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Purchase Order, Consignment Form, and Invoices, 1958-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material, 1958-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Basaldella, Dino (exhibition catalogue), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Basaldella, Mirko (biographical materials and printed material), 1950s-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Birolli, Renato (Box 1)
    - Biographical Material, 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1975, (16 folders) (Box 1, Folder 9-24)
    - Claim Against Galerie Springer, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bank Drafts relating to Sale of Artwork, 1955, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - List of Sales, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Notes, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Writings by Others,1951, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1952, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Exhibition Catalogues at the Catherine Viviano Gallery,1951-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Exhibition Catalogues (at other venues), circa 1950s-1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Reproductions (1946, undated), undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Clippings, 1956-1962, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material,circa 1959 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1950-1959), undated, (9 folders) (Box 1, Folder 37-45)
  - Broderson, Robert (Box 1)
    - Biographical Material, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1974, undated, (10 folders) (Box 1, Folder 47-56)
    - Catalogue Essay on Robert Broderson, circa 1961 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Sales and Expense Reports,1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Notes and Lists relating to Artwork, 1961-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Notes, Guest Lists, and List for Robert Broderson Exhibition, circa 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Shipping and Loan Receipts, 1961, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Exhibition Announcements, 1958, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Exhibition Catalogues (Catherine Viviano Gallery), 1961-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 63-64)
    - North Carolina Museum - "Award Winners" (1960 February 7-28), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Duke University - "Robert Broderson, Recent Works" (1963 November 20-December 15), 1963 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Clippings, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Press Release and Ceremonial Booklet from the American Academy and National Institute Award's to Robert Broderson, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1964-1965, (11 folders) (Box 1, Folder 70-80)
  - Brown, Carlyle (biographical material and artist's statement), 1950s (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Cox, Jan (Box 1)
    - Biographical Material, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Correspondence (includes exhibition brochures), 1969-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Cremonini, Leonardo (Box 1)
    - Biographical Material, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Announcements, Reproductions, Printed Material, and Photograph of Artwork, 1969-1977, undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - DeSiqueria, Nino (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1975, undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Exhibition Catalogue, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Dolci, Danilo, 1970-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Ekstrom, Thea (biographical material), circa 1964 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Franesconi, Anselmo (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1969, undated, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 91-95)
    - Exhibition Brochure,1954 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Sale of Artwork, 1955-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Lists of Artwork, circa 1955-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Miscellaneous Packing Receipt, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Sketch by Alfred Marinier, undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1957-1959, undated), undated, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 101-103)
  - Glasco, Joseph (Box 1)
    - Biographical Material (includes artist's statement), circa 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1976, undated, (7 folders) (Box 1, Folder 105-111)
    - Contemporary Arts Museum - "Joseph Glasco, 1948-1986: A Sesquintennial Exhibition" (1986), (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 112-114)
    - Sales and Expense Reports, 1951-1970 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Exhibition Catalogues (annotated with sales prices), 1954-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 116-117)
    - Exhibition Catalogues (other venues), 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Notes and Lists, 1958-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - List of Names, circa 1962-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Receipts, 1953-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - Customer Statement of Cable Transfer, Bank Deposit Receipts, and Debit Advice Slips, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - Clippings on Joseph Glasco, 1956-1979 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Lanyon, Peter (Box 2)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letter, Postcards, and Notes, 1969-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Exhibition Catalogue, 1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mabe, Manabu (Box 2)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Sales and Expenses Reports, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition Catalogues (annotated with sales prices), 1968-circa 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Exhibition Announcement, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Lists of Artwork (includes prices and appraisal valuations), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition Brochures and Catalogue for Manabu Mabe and Tomie Ohtake, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Notes, 1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Clipping,1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Photographs of Manabu Mabe, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1968-1970, undated), undated, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
  - Manrique, César (Box 2)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1966, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1975, undated, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 21-25)
    - Exhibition Catalogue (annotated with sales prices), 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - List of Paintings, circa 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Guest Lists, 1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bank Statements, Deposit Slips, and Shipping Receipts,1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Exhibition Announcements (other venues), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Clippings, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Photographs of César Manrique, circa 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1964-1969, undated), undated, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 34-40)
    - Photographs, Various Snapshots (1968, undated), 1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Negatives of Artwork (1969, undated),undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous Photograph, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Minguzzi, Luciano (Box 2)
    - Biographical Material, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1975, (15 folders) (Box 2, Folder 45-59)
    - Artist's Statement on the Fifth Door of the Duomo, circa 1957 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Sales of Artwork, 1957-1967 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Lists, Statements, and Invoices, 1956-1969 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Notes and Lists, circa 1956-1959, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 64-65)
    - American Federation of Artists - "Major Work in Minor Scale" (1955 September-1956 September),1955 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Exhibition Catalogues and Announcement (Catherine Viviano Gallery), 1955, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Exhibition Brochures (other venues), 1960, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Clippings, 1961-1974 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Reproductions of Artwork, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1949-1968, undated), undated, (13 folders) (Box 2, Folder 72-84)
    - Photograph of Exterior Building, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Negatives for the Fifth Door of the Duomo, Milan, Italy (1951-1957), undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Morlotti, Ennio (Box 2)
    - Biographical Information, Affidavit of Support for the Temporary Visitor, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1959, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 88-93)
    - Writings on Ennio Morlotti (including Catherine Viviano's statement on Ennio Morlotti), 1949-1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Notes and Lists, circa 1950s (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Lists of Artwork Returned, 1951-1959 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Shipping Statements and Receipt, 1951-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Exhibition Catalogues, 1951-1959 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Clipping, circa 1949 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Photograph of Artwork, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Perlin, Bernard (Box 2)
    - Biographical Material and Letter, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1976, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 102-108)
    - Notes, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Sales and Expense Reports, 1955-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Receipts, 1959-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Exhibition Catalogues (annotated with sale prices), 1955-1970 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Exhibition Catalogues, 1949-1966, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 113-114)
    - Guests Lists for Exhibition Openings, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Lists of Collectors of Bernard Perlin's Artwork, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Press Release, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Printed Material, 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Miscellaneous Items, 1954-1958, undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1948-1970, undated), undated, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 120-124)
  - Pirandello, Faustus (Box 3)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1957, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
    - Lists of Sales of Artwork, 1955-1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Catalogue, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1954, undated), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pizzinato, Armando (Box 3)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Sales of Artwork Returned, circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition Brochure, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Clipping, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Photographs of Artwork (circa 1949-1950), undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rice, Daniel (Box 3)
    - Biographical Material and Artist's Statement, circa 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Sales and Expenses, 1960-1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Invoices, Statements, and Receipts, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Catalogues, 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Photographs of Artwork (1959-1971), undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Rollo, Joseph (Box 3)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)